{"question": "Directory listening", "answer": "ls"}
{"question": "Formatted listening", "answer": "ls -l"}
{"question": "Formatted listening including hidden files", "answer": "ls -la"}
{"question": "Change directory", "answer": "cd"}
{"question": "Change to parent directory", "answer": "cd.."}
{"question": "Show the path where you actually are", "answer": "pwd"}
{"question": "Create a directory", "answer": "mkdir"}
{"question": "Remove a directory", "answer": "rm -r"}
{"question": "Force remove", "answer": "rm -f"}
{"question": "Copy file", "answer": "cp"}
{"question": "Rename or move file", "answer": "mv"}
{"question": "Create file", "answer": "touch"}
{"question": "Output contents of file", "answer": "cat file"}
{"question": "Write standard input into file", "answer": "cat > file"}
{"question": "Append standard input into file", "answer": "cat >> file"}
{"question": "Output contents of file it grows", "answer": "tail -f file"}
{"question": "Ping host", "answer": "ping host"}
{"question": "Show the actually routing table", "answer": "route -n"}
{"question": "Show the current date and time", "answer": "date"}
{"question": "Show this month\u00b4s calendar", "answer": "cal"}
{"question": "Show current uptime", "answer": "uptime"}
{"question": "Who you are logged in as", "answer": "Whoami"}
{"question": "Display information about user", "answer": "finger"}
{"question": "Shows user information", "answer": "Users / id"}
{"question": "Shows manual of command", "answer": "man command"}
{"question": "Shows your user name", "answer": "username"}
{"question": "Display who is online", "answer": "who / w"}
{"question": "Check your iptable\u00b4s rules", "answer": "iptables -L"}
{"question": "List all ports", "answer": "netstat -a"}
{"question": "Got whois for domain", "answer": "whois domain"}
{"question": "Get DNS for domain", "answer": "dig domain"}
{"question": "Reserve lookup host", "answer": "dig -x host"}
{"question": "Download file", "answer": "wget file"}
{"question": "Recurively download files from url", "answer": "wget -r url"}
{"question": "Outputs the webpage from url", "answer": "curl url"}
{"question": "Connects to host as user", "answer": "ssh user@host"}
{"question": "Connect using port", "answer": "ssh -p port user@host"}
{"question": "Connect and use bind port", "answer": "ssh -D user@host"}
{"question": "Display currently active processess", "answer": "ps"}
{"question": "Detailed outputs", "answer": "ps -aux"}
{"question": "Kill process id (pid)", "answer": "kill pid"}
{"question": "kill all processess named proc", "answer": "killall proc"}
{"question": "Display cpu info", "answer": "cat /proc/cpuinfo"}
{"question": "Memory info", "answer": "cat /proc/meminfo"}
{"question": "Show memory and swap usage", "answer": "free"}
{"question": "Show directory space usage", "answer": "du"}
{"question": "Display readable size of directory space usage in GB", "answer": "du -sh"}
{"question": "Show disc usage", "answer": "df"}
{"question": "Show kernel config", "answer": "uname -a"}
{"question": "tar files into file.tar", "answer": "tar -cf file.tar files"}
{"question": "Untar into current directory", "answer": "tar -xf file.tar"}
{"question": "Show contents of archive", "answer": "Show contents of archive"}
{"question": "Show contents of archive options: create archive", "answer": "c"}
{"question": "Show contents of archive options: table of contents", "answer": "t"}
{"question": "Show contents of archive options: extract", "answer": "x"}
{"question": "Show contents of archive options: use zip/gzip", "answer": "z"}
{"question": "Show contents of archive options: specify filename", "answer": "f"}
{"question": "Show contents of archive options: do not overwrite", "answer": "k"}
{"question": "Show contents of archive options: verbose", "answer": "v"}
{"question": "Change permission of file", "answer": "chmod rights file"}
{"question": "Change permission of file - read", "answer": "4 / r"}
{"question": "Change permission of file - write", "answer": "2 / w"}
{"question": "Change permission of file - execute", "answer": "1 / x"}
{"question": "Change permission of file - order", "answer": "owner, group, world"}
{"question": "Change permission of file - rwx for everyone", "answer": "chmod 777"}
{"question": "Change permission of file - rw for owner, rx for group and world", "answer": "chmod 755"}
{"question": "Search in files for patterns", "answer": "grep 'patterns' files"}
{"question": "Search for pattern recursively in dir", "answer": "grep -r 'pattern' dir"}
{"question": "Find all instances of file", "answer": "locate file"}
{"question": "Show possible locations of app", "answer": "whereis app"}
{"question": "View a file page by page", "answer": "less"}
{"question": "Output the the contents of file", "answer": "more"}
{"question": "Output the first 10 lines of file", "answer": "head"}
{"question": "Output the last 10 lines of file", "answer": "tail"}
{"question": "Display file page by page", "answer": "page"}
{"question": "View first 20 lines of file", "answer": "head -20 file"}
{"question": "View last 20 lines of file", "answer": "tail -20 file"}
{"question": "Create file and allow to write", "answer": "cat > filename"}
{"question": "Remove a empty directory", "answer": "rmdir"}
{"question": "Remove a directory", "answer": "rm -rf"}
{"question": "Find content difference in 2 files", "answer": "diff"}
{"question": "Search and replace particular pattern", "answer": "sed"}
{"question": "Show what kind of file it is", "answer": "file"}
{"question": "List all commands executed by a user", "answer": "history"}
{"question": "Free memory of a server", "answer": "free"}
{"question": "find option for searching a file with its name", "answer": " find -name filename"}
{"question": "find option for files whose owner is a particular user", "answer": "find -user username"}
{"question": "find option for files belonging to a particular group", "answer": "find -group groupname"}
{"question": "Permissions read only", "answer": "r / 4"}
{"question": "Permissions write only", "answer": "w / 2"}
{"question": "Permissions execute only", "answer": "x / 1"}
{"question": "Permissions read and write", "answer": "rw / 6"}
{"question": "Permissions read and execute", "answer": "r-x / 5"}
{"question": "Permissions write and execute", "answer": "wx / 3"}
{"question": "Permissions read & write & execute", "answer": "rwx / 7"}
{"question": "Linux file type Symbols - normal file", "answer": "-"}
{"question": "Linux file type Symbols - block file (harddisk / floppy disk)", "answer": "b"}
{"question": "Linux file type Symbols - character file (keyboard / mouse)", "answer": "c"}
{"question": "Linux file type Symbols - directory", "answer": "d"}
{"question": "Linux file type Symbols - link files (short cut)", "answer": "l"}
{"question": "Show how many file systems on the system", "answer": "df"}
{"question": "Show in mb how many file systems on the system", "answer": "df -m"}
{"question": "Show your current ip address", "answer": "ifconfig"}
{"question": "Port Number of FTP", "answer": "21"}
{"question": "Port Number of SSh", "answer": "22"}
{"question": "Port Number of TELNET", "answer": "23"}
{"question": "Port Number of SMTP", "answer": "25"}
{"question": "Port Number of DNS", "answer": "53"}
{"question": "Port Number of HTTP", "answer": "80"}
{"question": "Port Number of HTTPS", "answer": "443"}
{"question": "Show wich ports are used on your system", "answer": "netstat -tulpn"}
{"question": "Controls the starting and stopping of services", "answer": "service"}
{"question": "To check the status of the service", "answer": "service servicename status"}
{"question": "To start the service", "answer": "service servicename start"}
{"question": "To stop the service", "answer": "service servicename stop"}
{"question": "To reload the service", "answer": "service servicename reload"}
{"question": "To restart the service", "answer": "service servicename restart"}
{"question": "Controls which service are set to start on boot", "answer": "chkconfig"}
{"question": "To check the availability of a service", "answer": "chkconfig --list--"}
{"question": "To make the srvice available after restart", "answer": "chkconfig servicename on"}
{"question": "To make the service unavailable after restart", "answer": "chkconfig servicename off"}
{"question": "List the process which are running on the system", "answer": "ps -ef"}
{"question": "kill a process or service", "answer": "kill / kill -9"}
{"question": "run a program in the foreground", "answer": "fg"}
{"question": "Run the service in the background", "answer": "bg"}
{"question": "List top 20 processes which are consuming more CPU", "answer": "top"}
{"question": "Create a compressed zip file", "answer": "gzip"}
{"question": "Unzip a file", "answer": "gunzip"}
{"question": "List all actual cronjobs", "answer": "crontab -l"}
{"question": "Create a cronjob", "answer": "crontab -e"}
{"question": "Create a soft link (shortcut file)", "answer": "ln -s"}
{"question": "Create a hard link (backup file)", "answer": "ln"}
